

Recent graduate from Christopher Newport University with Bachelor's and Master's degrees in Computer Science. Seven years of work experience in varied fields such as tutoring, teaching, and software engineering. Diversified skill-sets covering object-oriented programming, functional programming, data structures with an emphasis on graphs, and problem solving.

## **Education**

## Academic Qualifications...

Christopher Newport University

M.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.88

Thesis: Planning Footsteps of Humanoid Robots

**Christopher Newport University** 

B.S. in Computer Science, Cum Laude, GPA: 3.52

Newport News, VA

Aug. 2016 - May 2018

Newport News, VA

Aug. 2012 - May 2016

## Notable Projects.....

o Masters Thesis: 'Planning Footsteps of Humanoid Robots'

I worked with Team ViGIR's open source footstep planner to create an accurate configuration for a small laboratory robot, as well as fix bugs that prevented accurate 2D planning. This involved learning about many different frameworks and systems to understand the system. Additionally, I implemented a custom plugin in the system.

Undergraduate Capstone: 'Data Visualization of Theoretical High-Energy Physics Papers'
Using tools such as JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap3, and D3js, I was able to generate a graph of archived papers in a large database, linked by citations. The intent was to create a visual gatekeeping system for academics.

# **Previous Employment**

### Port Technology Services

Norfolk, VA

Software Engineer

May 2017-Nov. 2017

Developed front ends for web applications using Angular 2/4+, Redux, and TypeScript. Debugged our CI/CD pipeline which consist of TeamCity and Octopus Deploy. Helped establish JIRA as the primary issue tracker and helped develop the workflow for issues.

#### **Christopher Newport University**

Newport News, VA

Graduate Lab Assistant

Aug. 2016-Aug. 2017

Instructed students in intermediate Java concepts: Inheritance, polymorphism, fundamental abstract data containers, file I/O, etc. Additionally, taught students how to use basic version control: adding, pulling, pushing, and merging simple conflicts.

## **Christopher Newport University**

Newport News, VA

Computer Science Tutor

Sep. 2014-Aug. 2016

Tutored students on HTML, JavaScript, Python and Java. The majority of the work was intermediate Java help.

### iD Tech Camps

Williamsburg, VA

Lead Instructor

Jun. 2016-Aug. 2016

Administered medications on a daily basis, performed first-aid as needed. Tutored and mentored students in Java, Python, and C++.

## **Technical and Personal skills**

- Programming Languages: Proficient in: Java/C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, LaTeX, ROS Also basic ability with: C++.
- o General Business Skills: Good presentation skills, works well in a team.
- o Other: Can write well organised and structured reports.